<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on BigEatie&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://bigeatie.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on BigEatie&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bigeatie.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does the Integral Power Law Hold for $x^{-1}$</title>
      <link>https://bigeatie.com/posts/integration-power-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bigeatie.com/posts/integration-power-law/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Method of Images</title>
      <link>https://bigeatie.com/posts/method-of-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bigeatie.com/posts/method-of-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The method of images is almost a real life mathematical cheat code. Imagine being able to solve what happens due to some intricate arrangement of charges on a conducting surface, but pretending as though it&amp;rsquo;s a single point charge. When I first saw this, I was quite stunned. It seems absurd that to solve one problem you solve, more or less, a completely separate problem. However the clever application of a mathematical principle ensures that the solutions to the two problems are the same. Instead of solving a hard physics problem it allows you to solve a much easier, barely related problem, and then insist that the solution to the two is the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Filtering of Chess Databases with pgn-extract</title>
      <link>https://bigeatie.com/posts/pgn-extract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bigeatie.com/posts/pgn-extract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Serious Chess players often rely on databases containing millions of games to enhance their studies. These databases are invaluable for studying openings, where a user can enter an exact sequence of moves to reach the position they want to analyze. Chess databases can filter based on such opening sequences with ease. However, when it comes to filtering based on criteria outside of the opening, such as games where there are more than eight minor pieces on the board, games that end in Anastasia&amp;rsquo;s mate, or games where advanced players tackle difficult rook and pawn endings your typical database falls short without external tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
